All right, so in this video then,
we are going to discuss some common
resource management tools and really most
of this refers to team resources, right?
But some of it, some of these tools can
include physical resources as well.
So these are tools for mostly for the
project manager, right?
But also we'll be discussing some tools
for team members as well.
Now, pre-assignment, right?
we need to assign team members to our
project, right?
We're going to assign team members to a
role and our project.
So how we're going to select our team
members?
Well, there's various different tools that
we use, that project manager will use.
One of them, for example, surveys,
attitudinal surveys.
So an attitudinal survey, basically is a
good measure of how people actually work.
and are they the right fit for the team?
And not only that, but within a project,
you may have several teams, well,
which team are they a right fit for,
based on their skill sets, right,
also based on their personality and based
on, you know, based
on other factors as well.
Right, so that's an attitudinal survey
then can help identify that.
An attitudinal survey
demonstrates a candidate's ability
to be flexible and adaptable,
right, and open to change.
Change is all around, right?
The world is constantly changing.
So business is constantly changing.
And so the work within an organization is
constantly changing, right?
So in the current environment,
and especially, you know, we're working in
an international setting as well,
we need to meet the client needs.
and because the world is constantly
changing, the work is constantly changing,
people need to adapt.
In fact, by definition, a project is a
change.
Remember the definition of
a project, temporary endeavor
undertaken to create a unique
product, service, or result.
Unique is a key word there.
That unique basically
means it's different to
what we had, different
to what we had before.
And so if it's different to what we had
before, it's something.
new.
And so the Actudinal survey then can
determine, you know, if this person is a
right fit for your team or for another
team.
Or, you know, maybe this person is not fit
at all.
Another tool you'll be using is this one
called specific assessment.
Specific assessment also
refers down to here, the last
bullet point refers to
also the ability test, right?
They're very similar, basically showing a
skill gap assessment.
So sometimes when
you're interviewing people,
you may show, give them a little test.
So like that for a developer,
you're hiring a developer,
I just ask them to write
a piece of code, right?
See how well they actually, you know,
how well they can actually perform.
Do they actually know, you know,
does actually know the work?
So again, these are ways of hiring team
members.
Right.
So this falls under
preassignment tools, right,
you're pre-assigning team
members onto your project.
And of course, the most common way is an
interview, right?
Structured interview, that's the most
common way of hiring team members,
obviously, you know, asking questions and
asking about their background.
And then also focus groups, and you may
have focus groups.
Focus group is basically bringing in a
group of subject matter experts or a group
of pre-assigned stakeholders and getting
their opinions, asking them questions.
Now, other tools then, negotiating,
right?
This is a very, very important skill set
for a project manager, negotiating skills.
So again, these are tools and techniques
for resource management, right?
So getting the right people, the right
skill sets, but also, you know,
other resources as well, physical
resources as well as team resources.
So as a project manager, you might need to
negotiate your roles
responsibilities as well.
So what's your authority level on the
project?
You might need to negotiate that.
Also, your priorities.
Also, remember in an agile environment,
right?
So this actually goes for both the team as
well as, say, the team facilitator and in
an agile environment, you are going to be
prioritizing user stories.
So within a sprint, the team themselves
are going to be prioritizing user stories.
So that's a type of
negotiation, which is a higher
priority, which are a lower
priority and so on and so forth.
As a project manager
as well, you might be,
not you might be in a
predictive environment.
As a project manager, you will be
assigning team members, right?
Assigning team members to different roles.
Well, the team members might negotiate
with you as well.
Whether they want to be in this role or
whether they want to be in another role,
you yourself might negotiate with your
seniors.
As a project manager, whether you want to
be in this role, whether you prefer to
manage this team or
another team, or whether,
you know, just your
responsibilities overall.
And of course, negotiation can be either
internal or external.
You're bringing in contractors and
consultants from outside.
So you're going to have different
negotiating skills versus internal, right?
Because if they're bringing them from
outside now, we've got contracts involved.
And so this leads over to procurement
management.
and there are the whole section on contracts
in the procurement management section.
Now, what we just talked about regarding
team members also applies to, at least
some of it also applies to physical
resources.
So we want to negotiate rooms, for
example, meeting rooms, conference rooms.
We need to book those in advance.
We need to negotiate equipment,
raw materials.
So they could be internal to the
organization.
We might be getting them from another
division or another department within the
organization or they could be external to
the organization.
Also, negotiating skills are needed for
the project team as well as a project
manager, such as things like service level
agreements.
SLA, service level agreements.
So as a simple example, we have to respond
back to our client within 24 hours.
They send us an email, they send us a
requirement, we have to respond within 24
hours or we have to respond within two
days.
So again, team members, project managers,
they might be negotiating that.
Are we going to respond within 24 hours?
Are we going to respond within one
business day?
Are we going to respond within three
business days and so on and so forth?
And then within the project itself,
there's many different agreements that
we're going to be negotiating,
right?
such as the scope of the project.
Statement of work refers to a procurement,
right?
And then procurement is hiring vendors who
are external to the organization,
but also the general scope of the project,
where if it's an internal project,
right?
So again, the scope of the project needs
to be negotiated, as well as the schedule
and milestones and budget, and these are
all separate knowledge areas, separate
videos on the schedule and the budget,
right?
Also negotiating warranties, terms and
conditions, dispute, dispute resolutions,
terms and conditions, dispute resolutions,
this is all external,
this is all procurement.
Again, we're going to cover those in the
procurement management section.
Okay, so these are just some of the skill
sets then that's required as a,
for resource management.
And there's for both, right, for both,
the project manager as well as a team.